二零二。
二一年中考英语真题听力特快专题内蒙古包头卷
听力。
听录音，根据各题要求选择最佳答案，并将答题卡上对应题目的答案标号
涂黑。
每项内容读两。
变。
第一节，听下面五段对话，根据你听到的内容选出相应的图片。
John, did you go to the museum to enjoy the works of art yesterday?
No, I helped my mother clean the
John, did you go to the museum to enjoy the of art yesterday?
No, I helped my mother clean the window
3. So you need some information on Chinese history?
Check the top shelf and you may find what you want
Oh, I see.
I want to borrow these four books
So you need some information on Chinese history?
Check the top shelf and you may find what you want Oh, I see.
I want to these four books
4. I'd like some fruit.
How much is the fruit over there?
The apples are 3 pounds a kilo.
The grapes are 4 pounds a kilo.
The bananas are 2 pounds a
I'd like some fruit.
How much is the fruit over there?
The apples are 3 pounds a kilo.
The grapes are 4 pounds a kilo.
The bananas are 2 pounds a kilo
5. Look! What is the robot doing?
Wow! It's serving food to customers.
How interesting it is!
5. What is the robot doing?
Wow! It's serving food to customers.
How interesting it is!
第二节听下面五段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题。
每小题五。
秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
听第六段材料，回答第六至八题。
Wow! It's serving 2 movie tickets.
Do you have time to go with me tonight?
Yes. But I remember that you dislike watching movies I used to.
Now I want to see a comedy
That's okay. I can't stand cartoons or documentaries
There's a comedy on at 7 o 'clock at Hongwu's cinema How can I get there?
You can take the number 4 bus and get off at the 6th stop.
The cinema is across from a supermarket
I see. How about meeting at the cinema at 6.30?
Okay. See you then
Mark, I have 2 movie tickets.
Do you have time to go with me tonight?
Yes. But I remember that you dislike watching movies I used to.
Now I want to see a comedy That's okay.
I can't stand cartoons or documentaries
There's a comedy on at 7 o at Hongwu's cinema How can I get there?
You can take the number 4 bus and get off at the 6th stop.
The cinema is across from a supermarket
I see. How about meeting at the cinema at 6.30?
Okay. See you then
听第七段材料，回答第九至十一题。
Hey, Tom. Please come in.
What would you like to Tea or juice?
Water is okay Okay.
Here you are Thanks.
How beautiful the paper cutting is.
Did your mother make it?
No, my neighbor made it and gave it to me before the spring festival.
I put them on windows, doors and walls as symbols of wishes for good luck
It seems to be a difficult job
That's true. Paper cutting sounds easy but it can be difficult to do.
I once learned it, but I could only make some easy patterns
Really? I want to learn it too
Hey, Tom. Please come in.
What would you like to drink?
Tea or juice?
Water is okay Okay.
Here you are Thanks.
How beautiful the paper cutting is.
Did your mother make it?
No, my neighbor made it and gave it to me before the spring festival.
I put them on windows, doors and walls as symbols of wishes for good luck It seems
to be a difficult job That's true.
Paper cutting sounds easy but it can be difficult to do.
I once learned it, but I could only make some easy patterns
Really? I want to learn it too
听第八段材料，回答第十二至十四题。
Excuse me, is this seat taken?
No. Let me help you with the big box
Thank you Do you want to sit by the window?
No. I like this seat better.
Please sit by the window if you like it
Okay. My name is Jack Brown.
Nice to meet you I'm Linda Miller.
Nice to meet you Do you live in
No, no. I'm from Florida, the USA.
I'm going to visit my son.
He works in London Me too.
Did you just get on the train?
No. I just changed my seat.
A man next to me was smoking, and smoke really made me feel terrible
Excuse me, is this seat taken?
No. Let me help you with the big box
Thank you Do you want to sit by the window?
No. I like this seat better.
Please sit by the window if you like it Okay.
My name is Jack Brown.
Nice to meet you I'm Linda Miller.
Nice to meet you Do you live in London?
No, no. I'm from Florida, the USA.
I'm going to visit my son.
He works in London Me too.
Did you just get on the train?
No. I just changed my seat.
A man next to me was smoking, and smoke really made me feel terrible
听第九段材料，回答第十五至十七题。
Mary, I know you're weak in math.
Do you need a teacher to help you on the weekend?
No thanks, dad.
My teacher says I have made a lot of progress Really?
Well done. Tell me more about your class, Mary Okay, dad.
There are 60 students in our class Are there more boys or more girls?
There are 28 boys and 4 more girls than boys in our class What about your teachers?
They are very good, aren't they?
Yes, especially our Chinese teacher, Mr.
What's he like?
He is kind and friendly to us I'm glad to hear that.
I think you will enjoy your middle school life in this school Yes, I hope so
Mary, I know you're weak in math.
Do you need a teacher to help you on the weekend?
No thanks, dad.
My teacher says I have made a lot of progress
Really? Well done.
Tell me more about your class, Mary Okay, dad.
There are 60 students in our class Are there more boys or more girls?
There are 28 boys and 4 more girls than boys in our class What about your teachers?
They are very good, aren't they?
Yes, especially our Chinese teacher, Mr.
What's he like?
is kind and friendly to us I'm glad to hear that.
I think you will enjoy your middle school life in this school
Yes, I hope so Xiao Ming had a dream last night.
听第十段材料，回答第十八至二十题。
In the dream, he worked as a tour guide in 'an He met a lot of people from abroad.
He communicated well with them in English He showed them around some famous places
in Xi 'an, such as museums, temples and parks Especially the Museum of the
Terracotta Army. They said they liked the museum's best in
With Xiao Ming's help, they learned a lot about Chinese culture They thought Xi was
an amazing city and China was a great country He smiled and smiled, and then he woke
up He hopes that his dream of being a guide will come true
Xiao Ming had a dream last night.
In the dream, he worked as a tour guide in He met a lot of people from abroad.
He communicated well with them in English He showed them around some famous places
in Xi 'an, such as museums, temples and parks Especially the Museum of the
Terracotta Army. They said they liked the museum's best in
With Xiao Ming's help, they learned a lot about Chinese culture They thought Xi was
an amazing city and China was a great country He smiled and smiled, and then he woke
up He hopes that his dream of being a guide will come true
He and then woke up
The Thank you for watching
听力测试到此结束。